<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-12-08T21:56:54+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Qiangjun Zhang</title><subtitle></subtitle><author><name>Qiangjun Zhang</name></author><entry><title type="html">Book review - Sapiens: A Brief History of Humankind by Yuval Noah Harari</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/12/07/book-review-sapiens.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Book review - Sapiens: A Brief History of Humankind by Yuval Noah Harari" /><published>2020-12-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-12-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/12/07/book-review-sapiens</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/12/07/book-review-sapiens.html">&lt;p&gt;Testing&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Qiangjun Zhang</name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html">Testing</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to my blog</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/12/04/welcome.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to my blog" /><published>2020-12-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-12-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/12/04/welcome</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/12/04/welcome.html">&lt;p&gt;In this special year, when we are all stuck at home during Coronavirus lockdown,
I finally made my mind, and decided to pursue a career as a software engineer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is not an easy decision for me.
After spent so many years in academia and earned a PhD in engineering,
everyone thought I will stay in academia and find a job in an University somewhere.
No doubt, it was difficult to explain to my friends why I made this decision,
actually many of them were shocked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was asked this question during interviews, I said, well, I enjoy coding
much more than writing papers. It is true, but the reasons are not as simple as
that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doing research is fun, and can be very rewarding.
My research is mainly scientific computing and numerical modelling.
In the past, I wrote codes to simulate the physical world, and now,
I probably have to write codes to sell more products, which does not sound very exciting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To many people, leaving academia means failure. There is no need to deny that.
For me, I know this is what I want to do. The good thing is that I have the skill sets that are needed for the software development work, and luckily, I got myself a job after two months of job hunting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before starting my new job, I built this website with two purposes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, maintaining a website is definitely a good way to learn new things and try some fun stuff.
Secondly, I believe writing is still a critical skill even though I don’t need to write journal papers, and blogging is the best way of practising it. It is quite different from academic writing though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Approaching the end of 2020, I do not know what life will bring me ahead,
but I am happy that I made this decision, and I look forward to the new chapter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blog/2020-12-04-01.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;My desk&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Qiangjun Zhang</name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html">In this special year, when we are all stuck at home during Coronavirus lockdown, I finally made my mind, and decided to pursue a career as a software engineer.</summary></entry></feed>